Guide to the George Amberg and Robert Gessner Papers 1913-1978 (Bulk 1940-1970) MC 199
New York University Archives
- Series V: Writings
  - Subseries B: Writings of Robert Gessner
    - "Some Notes on Cinematic Movements", 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - "Teaching is Sharing" U.S. Air Force Instructional Methods Part I, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Television Goes to College, 0000 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      Includes film programs 1957-1958
    - Treason, 0000 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Two Sides to the Equator: an original screen treatment, 0000 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      By Harold and Robert Gessner
    - Untitled Folder - "There is an African at the Gate", "Seven Faces of Time", "Teaching the Screenplay", 0000 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Untitled Folder - "Youth at the Studio Gate", "In Search of the Third Eye", "The Power Behind Polish Films", 0000 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - "We've Eliminated Every Neurosis but Jealousy", 0000 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Writings on Cinema, 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Writings - Notebooks, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Writings - Notebook, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Writings - Poetry, Prose, Score, 1934-1935, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - "The Year They Stopped the Commercials", 1963 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Series VI: Films
  - Currently undergoing evaluation and preservation at the NYU Library's Barbara Goldsmith Preservation and Conservation Department, 0000 (Box 12, 13)
- Series VII: Non-English Material
  - Box 14: Assorted Papers (film studio promotional material, film periodicals, typewritten memos, posters, art catalogs), 0000 (Box 14)
    barcode#:31142042278039
  - Box 15: Subject Files (film index cards with attached newspaper clippings, 1930s-1960s) (Box 15)
    This box contains an alphabetically filed collection of index cards, on which are printed newspaper clippings about feature films. The clippings provide information about the film's premise, the actors, the director, and local showing times. The films included in the box range in date from the 1930s to the 1960s.
    barcode#:31142042278047
  - Box 16: Photographs (prints from UNESCO Archives, portraits of filmmakers and film subjects) (Box 16)
    barcode#:31142042278054
- Series VIII: Scrapbooks
  - Treason, 1944 (Box 17)
  - Robert Gessner, 1945-1972 (Box 18)